Chapter 120. The deck towards the end of the first night watch.
Ahab standing by the helm. Starbucks approaching him. We must send down the
main topail yard, sir. The band is working loose and the Lee lift is half
stranded. Shall I strike it, sir? Strike nothing. Lash it. If I had sky sail
poles, I'd sway them up now, sir. In God's name, sir. Well, the anchors are
working, sir. Shall I get them in board?
Strike nothing and stir nothing, but lash everything. The wind rises, but it
has not got up to my table lands yet.
Quick and see to it. by masts and keels.
He takes me for the hunchbacked skipper of some coasting smack. Send down my
main top sail yard. Huh? Glue pots.
Loftiest trucks were made for wildest winds. And this brain truck of mine now
sails amid the cloud scud. Shall I strike that? Oh, none but cowards send
down their brain trucks in tempest time.
What a huru shaloft there. I would even take it for sublime. Did I not know that
the collic is a noisy malady? Oh, take medicine. Take medicine.